Guide to the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, Subject Files, 1963-present UPG.RG.52
ULS Greensburg
University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, Subject Files
1963-present
ULS Greensburg
University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
UPG.RG.52
24 boxes
Subject Files of the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, 1963-present.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Custodial History
Transferred from the UPG Administration to the UPG Archives.
Scope and Content Notes
Subject Files A-Z
Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Greensburg -- Records and correspondence; Universities and colleges -– Pennsylvania -– Greensburg -– Administration; University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
- Aaron Slafka Memorial Service Award, 2016-present (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
  Scope and Content Notes
  2016 Laronn Brown 2017 Mitchell Kirk 2018 Amanda Smith 2019 Kaylee Hauck
- Academic Villages (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
  See Also
  See also: UPG.RG.52 Subject Files. Ser.: Posters See also: UPG.RG.02.4 Ser.: Resource File for We Made No Small Plans: A Memoir
- Activities Fair (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
  See: UPG.RG.38 Student Information Fair
- Adult Education Classes, 2018-present (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
  2018, June 5, June 12. "Baby Boomer Retirement Course: The Rules Have Changed." [n.b.: Class held at Pitt Greensburg but not a program officially offered by UPG. Per faz 6/12/18] 2019, Mar. 14-Mar. 21. "Baby Boomer Retirement Course: The Rules Have Changed."
- Ambassadors (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
  See: UPG.RG.52 UPG Ambassadors [UPG Presidential Ambassadors]
- American Heart Association (Westmoreland County) [Westmoreland American Heart Association], 1999-2007 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
  Contains information on the UPG Heart Association, Heart Walk, and Heart Cup.
- American Red Cross of Westmoreland County, 2009-2016 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
  Blood Drive 2009, 2011, 2013, 2015, 2016
  Charitable Basketball Game 2009, 2011
  See also: UPG.RG.60 Prints. Faculty & Staff vs. Students Charity Basketball Game
- Anniversaries [UPG Anniversaries] (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
  See: UPG.RG.00 History. Anniversaries, 25th, 40th, 45th
  See also: UPG.RG.55 News Clippings [year of anniversary]
- Arthur St. Clair Lectureship: Celebrating Westmoreland County History, 2000-present (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  1st., Oct. 19, 2000. Dr. Eric A. Hinderaker
  2nd, Oct. 18, 2001. Dr. Colin Gordon Calloway
  3rd, Oct. 17, 2002. Dr. John Majewski
  4th, Oct. 16, 2003. Dr. Kenneth Warren, Emeritus Fellow of Jesus College, Oxford University.
  5th, Oct. 13, 2004. Dr. Matthew C. Ward, Prof. of History, University of Dundee, Scotland. [UPG Archives holds text of lecture in print format only. faz 10/18/11]
  6th, Oct. 12, 2005. Dr. Fred Anderson, Prof. of History, University of Colorado at Boulder
  7th, Oct. 11, 2006. Dr. Franklin K. Toker. University of Pittsburgh Architectural Historian.
  8th, Oct. 10, 2007. Dr. Anne Mosher, Professor of Geography, Syracuse University. [Poster in Map Case] [Note: no text in any format available. faz 10/18/11]
  9th, Oct. 8, 2008. Dr. Michael McConnell, Professor of History, Universtity of Alabama at Birmingham. [Poster in Map Case.] [UPG Archives holds text of this lecture in print form only.]
  10th, Oct. 24. 2009. Dr. Devra Davis, Professor of Epidemiology, University of Pittsburgh Graduate School of Public Health.
  11th, Oct. 6th, 2010. Sir David Cannadine, British scholar, historian, and author of Mellon: An American Life. [Poster in Map Case]
  12th, Oct. 12, 2011. Dr. David Nasaw, Distinguished Professor of American History, Graduate Center of the City University of New York
  13th, Oct. 10, 2012. Dr. Frank A. Cassell, Colonial Historian, Retired President, University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg. [Poster in Map Case]
  14th, Oct. 21, 2013. Harold Holzer, the Metropolitan Museum of Art's senior vice president for external affairs and a leading authority on Abraham Lincoln and the political culture of the Civil War era. "Emancipating Lincoln: The Prose and Poetry of the Emancipation Proclamation." [Poster in Map Case]
  15th, Oct. 16, 2014. Terry Bouton, Assoc. Prof. of History, University of Maryland, Baltimore, MD, where he is a Presidential Teaching Professor and an Organization of American Historians Distinguished Lecturer. "Was the 'Whiskey Rebellion' really about Whiskey?"
  16th, Oct. 15, 2015. G. Terry Madonna, PhD, Prof. of Public Affairs, Franklin & Marshall College. Talk entitled, "Pennsylvania's Role in Presidential Politics--Past and Present."
  17th, Nov. 29, 2016 [rescheduled from Oct. 13, 2016]. Robert E. Eberley, Jr., author of "Bouquets from the Cannon Mouth: Soldiering with the eighth Regiment of the Pennsylvania Reserves."
  18th, Feb. 5, 2019. Susan Sommers, PhD, "Arthur S. Clair: Myth and History".
  For videocassettes of 1st-4th, 6th lectures, See: UPG.RG.60 VC VIII.7.a-e. For DVD of 7th lecture, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 3A. For DVD of 8th lecture, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 3B. For DVD of 11th lecture, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 3C. For DVD of 12th lecture, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 3D. For DVD of 13th lecture, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 3E. For DVD of 14th lecture, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 3F. For DVD of 15th lecture, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 3G. For DVD of 16th lecture, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 3H. For DVD of 17th lecture, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 3I. For DVD of 18th lecture, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 3J.
  For Posters See: qRG52 Arthur St. Clair Lectureship [Housed in Map Case]
- Art Show @ Pitt-Greensburg, 2017-present (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
  Historical Note: First annual art show as part of [UPG's] Blue & Gold Week [Homecoming] activities. It is intended to showcase the artistic talent of the campus community as well as the talent of those who live and work in southwestern Pennsylvania. It is supported, in part by UPMC, the show's "Collector Sponsor." [News Release 9/19/2019]
  1st Annual, 2017 Oct. 10-15 2nd Annual, 2018, Oct. 10-21 3rd Annual, 2019, Sept. 27-Oct. 10
- Art Works, 1971-2005
  - Neujahr [New Year] 1989 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
    A celebration of the unification of Germany in leaded glass, mirror, wood, and steel by Terry Bengel. 18' w X 6' h. Gift of the German Society of the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg in memory of Arthur F. and Whilamine E. Kuschmierz.
  - Fort Ligonier (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
    by artist Anthony Diminno
  - A Song from the Blue Field (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
    by artist Atsuko Oikawa: Japanese painting donated by Yuko Takahashi and hangs in The Joan Chambers Children's Literature Collection in Millstein Library
  - The Fountain of Life (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
    [Mary Lou Campana Chapel and Lecture Center], stained glass mural by Terry Bengel
  - Greensburg, Pa. 1971 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
    by Robert Qualters
  - Gimbel Pennsylvania Art Collection, 1986-1987 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
    Exhibition Catalog. An Exhibition Co-Sponsored by: the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg and Westmoreland Museum of Art 18 October - 1986 - November 16. University Art Gallery - University of Pittsburgh 9 January - 1987 - February 15.
    See also: UPG.RG.52 Ser.: Gimbel Pennsylvania Art Colleciton.
  - "Sit on it!", 2012 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
    [Chair designed and completed by UPG students, members of the Visual Arts Society, as part of the Westmoreland Museum of American Art exhibit, "The Art of Seating: 200 Years of American Design (Feb. 4-Apr.8, 2012," special event, "Sit on it!", a fun interpretation of chair design.]
  - Stained Glass Window--UPG Seal (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Folder unknown container)
    Installed in Chambers Hall, August, 1999. Piece made by Terry Bengel with glass created and donated by Youghiogheny Opalescent Glass Co., Connellsville, Pa. File includes artwork designs for the stained glass window.
  - Peacemaker, The (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
    [Portrait of Chief White Eyes.] Artist Robert Griffing. [A Paramount Press Canvas Ciclee Reproduction.] Hangs in Millstein Library on wall connecting rooms 166-168.
  - Upward to the Light, 1999-2006 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
    General File, 1999, 2003, 2004. File contains: correspondence, memoranda, in re project design, construction, installation and funding.
    [Proposed leaded glass artwork (12.5' x 28') for the Millstein Library Tower by Terry L. Bengel. 2003.]
    Stained glass mural. Installation. Tower, Millstein Library. 7/30-31, 8/1/04.
    The Dr. Paul Albert Chew Memorial Window. Dedication. May 14, 2005.
    See also: UPG.RG60. Prints. Art Works. "Upward to the Light". Installation. Prints. Art Works. "Upward to the Light", Views.
    See Also: UPG.RG.55 News Clippings. University Times, 1/19/06 p 10 for article on art works at UPG.
- Adult Education Classes, 2018 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 3)
  Baby Boomer Retirement Course. Mar, 6, 13, 20 [2018]
- Autism Conference, 2011-2013 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  1st, 2011
  2nd, 2012
  3rd, 2013
- Behavioral Sciences Academic Village (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  Residence Halls: Benjamin Franklin House; Margaret Mead House; Thurgood Marshall House
  See also: UPG.RG.52 Subject Files. Ser.: Posters.
- Blue & Gold Activities, 2011-2022 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  1st annual, 2011
  Golf Outing, 2022
- "Broadway Battles Breast Cancer", October 28, 2011 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  1st Broadway Battles Breast Cancer annual concert October 28, 2011.
  For programs of 1st and 2nd annual concerts, See: UPG Archives UPG.RG.52 Subject Files. Ser. Programs. For DVD of 1st annual concert, See: UPG Archives UPG.RG.60 DVD 19.
- Buildings [Facilities]
  See also: UPG Campus Community Committees. Space Allocation Committee; UPG.RG.01 Legal Papers-Property Agreements, Contracts; UPG.RG.02.1 President. Smith, Dr. Albert B., Jr. Addendum. Land Acquisitions.
  - Campus [Greensburg Campus, Hempfield Twp.] Construction, 1963-1965 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 5)
    See: UPG.RG.02.1 President. Smith, Dr. Albert B. Addendum. 2016-2017
  - Cassell Hall [Frank A. Cassell Hall] [Previously referred to as the Sustainable Office and Classroom Building (SOC)], 2012-2014 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 5)
    Named "Frank A. Cassell Hall" in a a resolution adopted by the University of Pittsburgh Board of trustees 2/24/12. Ribbon-Cutting Ceremony, September 5, 2012. File also contains: Program, The Construction Industry "Evening of Excellence" [construction awards], Thursday, Feb. 28, 2013, Heinz Field East Club; 2 dinner tickets; copy of MBA 2013-2015 Sourcebook; ltr [copy] dtd 3/17/14 S. Richard Fedrizzi to SPS in re "achieving LEED gold certification of the Frank A Cassell Hall..."; Booklet, "2012 MBA Building Excellence Awards".
    See UPG.RG.60 DVD25 for video disc of Ribbon Cutting Ceremony, Frank A. Cassell Hall, 9/5/12.
  - Chambers Hall (formerly called Common Facilities and was a.k.a. Student Center), 1987-1999 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 5)
    (for VC of renaming dedication ceremony June 20, 1997, see UPG.RG.60 VC II.2;for VC of original dedication of Common Facilities August 16, 1989, see UPG.RG.60 VC II.4).
    [File also contains: remarks by Dr. George F. Chambers at the dedication of the addition to the Student Activities Center; news release 11/12/87 in re construction of a Student Services Building; documents in re dedication of Student Activities Center (Student Center Proposal from Design Alliance 9/23/89, remarks by president at dedication, guest lists; news clippings). Dedication 8/16/89. Also includes 10th Anniversary (1989-1999) Souvenir Coaster].
  - Life Sciences Complex, 2021 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 5)
  - Lynch Hall (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 5)
    See also: UPG.RG.61 Audio Cassette C.14 for "Tour of Lynch Hall" by Dr. Albert Smith. Sept. 28, 1986.
  - Lynch Hall Gatehouse (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 5)
  - Marsh Psychology Laboratory [Diane T. Marsh Psychology Laboratory] (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 5)
    See: UPG.RG.51 Programs Dedication...Marsh Psychology Laboratory.
  - Mary Lou Campana Chapel and Lecture Center (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 5)
    See also: UPG.RG.52 Ser.: Programs (Dedication)—Mary Lou Campana Chapel and Lecture Center, Dedication Ceremony, Tuesday, November 13, 2007. See also UPG.RG.60 DVD8 for DVD Dedication Ceremony.
  - McKenna Hall [McKenna Hall Computing Center][Student Activity Center] (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 5)
  - Millstein Library (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 6)
    See also UPG.RG.60 VC II.5 for dedication ceremony, May 5, 1995. See also UPG.RG.52 Ser.: Programs [Dedication...] Millstein Library. See also UPG.RG.02.2 President Chambers, Dr. George F. Ser.: Subject Files. Library/Admin. Bldg. [Millstein Library]
  - Powers Hall, 1993-1994 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 6)
    [File includes documents in re "Interior Renovations and Addition 1993-1994", "A Brief History of the Development of UPG Physical Plant. [1963?]]
  - Robertshaw Hall (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 6)
    See also UPG.RG.60 VC II.4 for dedication ceremony August 22, 1989.
  - Safety and Security Center (SSC) (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 6)
    formerly Security and Information Center (SIC) renamed Safety and Security Center (SSC) in May, 2001
  - Westmoreland Hall (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 6)
    [Natural Sciences and New Technologies Academic Village Residence Hall]
- Various
  See Also: UPG.RG.02.4. President. Cassell, Dr. Frank A. Ser.: Memoranda. 2001, Feb. 9 Subj.: Approval of Building Names.
  See Also: UPG.RG.52 Subject Files--Programs (Dedication)
  See Also: UPG.RG.36 UPG Campus Community Committees. Ser: Task Force to Provide Advice on a Major Facilities Improvement Project (2003).
  See Also: UPG.RG.60 Prints - [Name of Building, Facility]; Construction Projects 2010
  See Also: UPG.RG.60 Prints - Construction Projects 2010
  - Behavioral Sciences Academic Village (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
    (Benjamin Franklin House; Margaret Mead House; Thurgood Marshall House)
  - Biology, Chemistry, Physics Laboratories (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
    (basement Smith Hall) Renovation
  - Chartwell's (Museum-cabinet 2, Box 3, Shelf 4)
  - Chapel (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Coffeehouse [The Exchange] (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
    See: UPG.RG.52 Coffeehouse [Coffeehouse-Open Mic Night; The Exchange]
  - College Hall (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Exercise Center (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Faculty Office Building (FOB) (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Ferguson Theater (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Fitness Center [UPG Fitness Center] [Ronnie Andrews Fitness Center] (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Gazebo (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
    See also: UPG.RG.05 Principals. Carl A. Rossman. Ser.: Memoranda. 2001, July 9.
  - Hempfield Room [in Chambers Hall] (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Humanities Academic Village (Apollo House; Athena House; Selene House) (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - International Academic Village [in Westmoreland Hall] (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Library Garden, The [A Memorial Garden and Meditation Area] [Reflection Garden], August 22, 2018 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
    Inscription, "The Library Garden in Memory of Bonnie Heather Chambers Millstein Library 1996-2017". Dedicated, Noon, Wednesday, August 22, 2018. Memorial designed by Joseph (Joe) Bleehash, Director of Facilities and Security. Landscaping and construction under the direction of JB. Memorial located on the north side of Millstein Library.
  - Lyceum, The (Natural Sciences and New Technologies Academic Village Hall) (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Natural Sci. and New Tech. Academic Village. Dormitory [Student Residence Facility] (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Outdoor Adventure and Community Services (OACS) Special Interest Housing [in Westmoreland Hall] (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Outdoor Recreational Area (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
    See: UPG.RG.52 Ser.: Programs (Dedication)--Outdoor Recreational Area
  - Plant Maintenance Bldg. [formerly called Chauffer's Cottage, Psychology Bldg., Pareto Hall, Pohl Bldg.] (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Rial House (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Ridilla Field (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Rossetti International House (formally called Quinn House, Terra House, Rossetti House) (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Smith Hall (formerly called Science Building) (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Softball Field (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - University Court (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
    See also: UPG.RG.02.2 President. Chambers, Dr. George F. Ser.: Memoranda. [1982] Memo. for the Ad. Bd. Tanglewood Chronicle.
  - Village Hall (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Vincent Finoli Drive (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Vogel Building (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
- Calendar of Events [University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Calender of Events] (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  See: UPG.RG.27 Ser.: News Releases: UPG.RG.50 Ser.: Serials. Intercom: UPG.RG.50 Ser. Serials. UPG [Electronic] Campus Calendar [Print Copy]
- Campana Biology Award, 2012-present (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  [n.b.: listing only; no File Folder]
  2012 Breanna Kerry 2013 Autumn Aldrich 2014 Andrew Wolff 2015 Benjamin Hampton 2016 Bethany Faoust. Justin Marin 2017 Aaliyah Winfey 2018 Marina Shenouda 2019 Carissa Berg
- Campana Biology Research Award, 2012-present (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  2012 Blessing Nduka 2013 Zachary Weisner 2014 Heather Metro 2015 Cayla Ray 2016 Kaylynn McKinney 2017 Sydney Geary; Taylor Holmes 2018 Stephen Moore 2019 Timothy Legenzoff
- Campana Math Awards, 2012-present (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  2012 Ryan Kunkle; Maria Germansky 2013 Dale Osselborn; David Coradi 2014 Lucas Dennison; Sean Welsh 2015 Rachel Haras, Christopher Cline 2016 Nicole Farkosh; Joshua Whitlinger 2017 Lyndy Baer; Edward Kuhn 2018 Kelcie King 2019 Eric Baer
- Campus Annual Agenda [Annual Agenda; Campus Agenda], 1997-2007 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 4, Box 1)
  1997/98 (1st), 1998/99 (2nd), 1999/2000 (3rd), 2000/01 (4th), 2001/02 (5th), 2002/03 (6th), 2003/04, 2004/05, 2005/06, 2005/06 Summary of Results, 2006/07
- Campus Challenge Food Drive (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 4, Box 1)
- Campus Climate Survey, 2007-2016 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 4, Box 1)
  1st, 2007 2nd, 2008 3rd, 2009 4th, 2010 5th, 2011 7th, Jan. 2014 8th, [Spring] 2015 9th, 2016
  See also: UPG.RG.02.5 Ser.: Memoranda. Memorandum dtd 1/14/08
- Campus Flower Fund (UPG Faculty and Staff), October 28, 1992-December, 2003 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 4, Box 1)
  Includes: Guidelines for Flower Fund; Flower Fund Contributors, Oct., 1997, 1997/98; Check Register, 10/28/92-8/7/03; Dollar Bank Account Statements, 10/28/92-8/12/99, 9/27/01-10/29/01, 8/23/03-11/27/03; Memoranda to faculty, staff and administration in re Flower Fund, 1992-1995, 1999-2003, 2005; letters conveying memorial donations to various organizations, institutions [1988-2003].
- Campus Surveys, 1999-2005 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 4, Box 2)
  Campus Survey '99. Preliminary Report: A Survey of Student Experiences at the University of Pittsburgh, Greensburg. June, 1999. Randi Koeske, Ph.D. [Research project conducted as part of Research Methods 1, (in Psychology) class at the University of Pittsburgh, Greensburg.
  Campus Survey 2000: Initial Implementation of an Academic Village at UPG. February, 2001. Randi Koeske, Ph.D. [Research project conducted as part of a
  Research Methods 1 (in Psychology) class at the University of Pittsburgh, Greensburg.] Includes: 2000 Campus Survey Project Report.
  Campus Survey 2001. A Survey of Student Experiences at UPG. Includes: UPG Campus Survey Report, June, 2002.
  Campus Survey 2002. "Survey of Student Reactions to the Campus". Includes UPG Campus Survey 2002--Basic Findings.
  Campus Survey 2003. [no Campus Survey conducted this year]
  Campus Survey 2004. "Student experiences at UPG...how effective the campus is addressing your needs as a student". [UPG Archives lacks Findings/Report]
  Campus Survey 2005. "Choosing a Major at UPG; an Exploration of Student Experiences in Fall 2005." Includes: Campus Survey 2005 Report. 7-12-06].
  See also: UPG.RG.02.4 Ser.: Resource File for We Made No Small Plans: A Memoir
- Capstone Presentations, 2006-2017 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 4, Box 2)
  See also, UPG.RG.52 Ser.: Programs (Miscellaneous) Functioning Dysfunctional [A UPG Visual and Performance Arts Capstone Peformance.]
  Includes: Pamphlet, Ready for Their Close-ups: Creative Nonfiction, Fiction and Poetry from the 2006 Capstone Readings. 44p.
  Includes: Pamphlet, Ready for Their Close-ups: The Fall English Writing Capstone Readings. December 2 & 4, 2008.
  Includes: Pamphlet, Open Reading: English Writing Capstones '11. April 5, 2011.
  Includes: News Release 4/14/2017 Pitt-Greensburg Creative and Professional Writing Majors Release Chapbooks; Reading and Book Signing Event set for April 19.
- Cave Canem Summer Workshop/Retreat, 2003-2008 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 4, Box 2)
  June 22-29, 2003. Includes: a poem, "Six Minute Dogfight, Clarence "Lucky" Lester, July 18, 1944" by Marilyn Nelson, Poet laureate of Connecticut and a participant in the 2003 Workshop/Retreat. This typed copy with a holograph note by MN and signed by MN was presented to "Clara [Vana], [librarian with Millstein Library] -- Many thanks for your help with this poem! Best Wishes". [Presented 27 July 2003 to CV.] File also contains information for Cave Canem Summer Workshop/Retreat 2004, 2005, 2008.
- Center for Applied Research (CFAR), 2013 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 4, Box 2)
  Established 2013
- Center for Professional Growth at Pitt-Greensburg (CPG at UPG), March 15, 2010 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 4, Box 2)
  Changed name on March 15, 2010 from Institute for Continued Learning (ICL)
- Center for the Digital Text, 2015 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 4, Box 2)
  Founded in 2015.
- Chancellor's Staff Award for Community Impact [Previously: Chancellor's Distingushed Service Award for Staff Employees: Chancellor's Award for Staff Excellence in Service to the Community, Chancellor's Award for Staff Excellence in Service to the University], 1997-2016 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 4, Box 2)
  1997 Carol Calloway 2001/2002 Janet Biskup 2004/2005 Sheila Confer 2011 Bryan M. Valentine 2014 Sheila Confer 2015 Brian Root 2016 Troy Ross
  [Historical Note] [The Chancellor's Distinguished Service Award for Staff Employees recognizes service excellence in the work place and volunteer service in the community. The award provides a $2500 cash award. Names of the awardees appear in the program of the Honors Convocation (Oakland) and are inscribed on a bronze plaque in the William Pitt Union.]
- Chancellor's Distinguished Teaching Award [Chancellor's Award for Distinguished Teaching], 1986-present (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 4, Box 2)
  The Chancellor's Distinguished Teaching Award provides a $2,000 cash award and a grant of $3,000 for support of teaching functions. Names of the awardees appear in the program for the Honors Convocation and are inscribed on a bronze plaque in the William Pitt Union.
  UPG winners of the Chancellor's Distinguished Teaching Award include: